Victor Ngo

29 Pembroke St. Unit N. Toronto, Ontario M5A 2N6 | (647)-226 6395 | victor2.ngo@ryerson.ca

December 2, 2017

Damon Tohidi AMD 1 Commerce Valley Dr. E Thornhill, ON L3T 7X6

Dear Damon Tohidi:

I am applying for the Serdes RTL Design Engineer Intern position that was posted on the AMD Careers Portal. Based on the requirements and job description, I strongly believe that this position aligns with my academic background, personal and career interests.

I am currently a third year Electrical Engineering student at Ryerson University. I have taken and performed well at a variety of courses with such as Electronic Circuits, Digital Systems, Algorithms and Data Structures and am currently taking Microprocessor Systems which are relevant to the position. I have been required to solve problems using a variety of circuit simulation software (Multisim) and digital logic, programming and debugging skills with VHDL, C, and Java. This semester, my courses require me to work with assembly language to program a HCS12 microcontroller, signal processing in MATLAB and design/implement analog circuits using op-amps and 555-timers. In addition, I have obtained fundamental knowledge of C++ and C# programming by doing personal projects such as Unity Engine Game design.

As for work experience, over this last summer I worked as a research assistant for OPR-Laboratory at Ryerson University. I found it to be an excellent opportunity to explore my interests and gain valuable experience. During my time I was introduced to image processing and cryptography, both of which I have developed an interest for. I would like to expand my range of knowledge and discover new interests through working with AMD.

My personal qualities include strong analytical and detail oriented problem-solving skills. I excel in both group and individual work. I have developed strong time management skills over my university career trying to balance part-time work with school and hobbies. Under pressure, I am able to keep a level head and focus on the task at hand. These skills are essential to working in a fast paced, technically challenging environment such as AMD's.

Being able to make an impact in the world has been a lifetime goal I've set for myself. After graduation, my career's sights are aimed at a position where I am able to push and innovate the future. It would be an amazing opportunity to be able to kick start my engineering career by contributing to the development of AMD's CPU technology.

Thank you for	your consideration an	d I look forward to	hearing back with	you soon.
, , , , , , , , , , , , , , , , , , ,	,		3	,

Sincerely,

Victor Ngo

Education

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING | EXPECTED GRADUATION: 2019 | RYERSON UNIVERSITY

- · Major: Electrical Engineering
- · Current CGPA: 3.81/4.33, Dean's List FEAS

Work Experience

RESEARCH ASSISTANT | OPR LABORATORY - RYERSON UNIVERSITY | MAY 2017 - SEPT 2017

- · Worked in a group to perform tasks given by the Principle Investigator (PI).
- · Tested and improved on existing implementation provided by the PI.
- · Developed analytical and project management skills
- · Obtained valuable experience with MATLAB, image processing and cryptography.
- · Presented findings and improvements on existing implementation to group members and the PI.

CO-DIRECTOR | TORONTO STUDENTS ADVANCING AEROSPACE | AUGUST 2016 - PRESENT

- Managed a group of undergraduate students that handles finances, logistics and content creation for yearly conference.
- · Developed budgeting, organizational skills with student groups.
- · Received over \$10,000 in funding for the 2016 conference.

MTH140 SLG FACILITATOR | STUDENT LEARNING SUPPORT – RYERSON UNIVERSITY | SEPT 2017 – PRESENT

- · Facilitates weekly discussion-based Supported Learning Groups (SLGs) to help students build their academic skills.
- · Developed public speaking and clear communication skills.
- · Demonstrated high knowledge of calculus 1 content,

LIFEGUARD AND SWIM INSTRUCTOR | CITY OF TORONTO | APRIL 2014 - PRESENT

- Maintained the health and safety of patrons and coworkers using scanning techniques and accident prevention style lifeguarding.
- · Developed strong communication and teamwork skills.

Projects and Competitions

SAS BIG DATA COMPETITION | ZONE LEARNING ANALYTICS SCHOOL - RYERSON | FEB 2017

- Task of competition was to provide insights and visual representation of the datasheets provided by the Ministry of Advanced Education and Skills Development (MAESD)
- · Obtained valuable experience with Big Data and data analysis.
- · Developed statistics, data visualization, team-building and presentation skills.

ALU DESIGN | COE328 FINAL PROJECT - RYERSON | NOVEMBER 2016

- · Designed an arithmetic logic unit using materials taught from the digital systems course.
- · The uniformed basic arithmetic and logic operations based on user input.
- · Used VHDL to program the Cyclone II FPGA board.

Programming and Computing Skills

- · Arduino Fundamental Knowledge
 - · Built an autonomous RC car using Arduino microcontroller and ultrasonic sensors.
- · C++ Fundamental Knowledge
 - · Used for personal project: turn-based game using IDE console.
- · C Intermediate
 - · Used C procedural programming to develop solutions to proposed course problems.
- · Java Intermediate
 - Used Java to solve problems proposed in courses through object oriented programming.
- · MATLAB Intermediate
 - · Used MATLAB software throughout the summer for image processing.
- · SAS Software (Data analysis software) Fundamental Knowledge
 - · Analyzed and developed data visualizations from datasheets provided from the government.
- · Unity Engine Fundamental Knowledge
 - Taking a course on 2D game development. Looking to start a project in the future.
- · C# Fundamental Knowledge
 - · Used C# to write scripts for processes in Unity Engine.
- · Algorithm Design and Data Structures
 - · Applied algorithm design, data structures and complexity analysis in courses to solve problems.
- · VHDL Fundamental Knowledge